Finding Aid for Michael Daugherty papers, 1973-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michael Daugherty papers 1973-2013
Daugherty, Michael, 1954-
38.5 linear feet (in 55 boxes and 1 oversize folder)
2011163 Aa 2 Ac
Michael Daugherty is an internationally renowned composer and Professor of Composition at the University of Michigan School of Music, Theatre & Dance. Papers include compositions and original scores, correspondence, reviews, previews, programs and brochures for performances of Daugherty’s work, and notes and collected materials documenting Daugherty’s education, awards, and grants.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Michael Daugherty (Donor no. 10620 ) in 2011. Additions were received in 2012.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Michael Daugherty is an internationally renowned composer and Professor of Composition at the University of Michigan School of Music, Theatre & Dance. Daugherty has composed dozens works since coming to national attention in the United States when Snap! -- Blue Like an Orange (1987) won a Kennedy Center Feldheim Award in 1989. He gained international attention in 1994 when his Metropolis Symphony was performed at Carnegie Hall. Daugherty uses sophisticated compositional techniques and complex polyrhythmic layers and is well-known for integrating electronic, jazz, rock, and contemporary American pop music with traditional concert music. From the late 1980s to mid-1990s Daugherty completed a series of compositions focused on twentieth-century American cultural icons, including Desi (1991), a Latin big band tribute to Desi Arnaz, Dead Elvis (1993), Metropolis Symphony (1988-1993) and Bizarro (1993), inspired by the Superman comic strip of the 1950s and 1960s, and Motown Metal (1994). In the late 1990s Daugherty explored geographic themes, including, Niagara Falls (1997), Route 66 (1998), and Motor City Tryptich (2000). Over the last decade, his compositions have begun to include subjects drawn from American history, including Trail of Tears (2010), Letters from Lincoln (2009), and Bay of Pigs (2006).
Daugherty's compositions have been recorded and made available by Delos, Naxos, Argo, Nonesuch, and several other recording labels. The 2011 Naxos recording of the Nashville Symphony Orchestra's performance of Metropolis and Deus ex Machina received three Grammy awards, including Best Classical Contemporary Composition. Among the many other rewards he has received are the Detroit Music Awards Outstanding Classical Composer (2007, 2009, 2010), the Stoeger Prize from the Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center (2000), and the Lancaster Symphony Orchestra Composer's Award (2005). Daugherty has won fellowships from the National Endowment for the Arts (1992) and the Guggenheim Foundation (1996).
Daugherty was born in Cedar Rapids, Iowa in 1954 and attended college at North Texas State University. After graduating with a B.Mus. in 1976, he studied at the Manhattan School of Music where he received his M.Mus. in 1978. From 1979 to 1980 Daugherty studied computer music at Institut Recherche et Coordination Acoustique/Musique (IRCAM) as a Fulbright Fellow. Upon returning to the United States, Daugherty enrolled at Yale University's School of Music and received his Doctor of Music degree in 1986. He taught at the Oberlin Conservatory of Music from 1986-1990 and joined the faculty of the University of Michigan School of Music, Theatre & Dance in 1991. He has also been Composer-in-Residence with several symphonies and music festivals, including the Detroit Symphony Orchestra (1999-2003), Music from Angel Fire Chamber Music Festival (2006), and the Pacific Symphony (2010).
The Michael Daugherty papers document the career of composer Michael Daugherty. The collection consists of thirteen series: Biographical Materials, Compositions and Original Scores, Programs, Previews, Reviews, Brochures and Other Promotional Materials, Education and Awards, Correspondence, Contacts and Calendars, Media, Published Scores, Teaching Materials, and Miscellaneous. The collection includes compositions and original scores, programs, previews, brochures, other promotional materials, reviews of performances of Daugherty's compositions, notes and compositions from Daugherty's education, lecture notes and ideas, biographical materials, correspondence, and material documenting awards and fellowships received. The strength of the collection lies in the compositions and original scores and the collected programs, previews, reviews, and promotional materials that document performances of Daugherty's compositions.
Subjects:
Composers--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Music, Theatre & Dance.
Genre Terms:
Scores.
- Biographical Materials
  The Biographical Materials series documents Daugherty's lifetime creative achievements and professional background. Materials include biographical notes for performance programs, curriculum vitas and lists of performance and compositions, and materials from his interview with the University of Michigan School of Music Theatre, & Dance.
  - Miscellaneous Program Notes 1996, 1998, undated (Box 1)
  - University of Michigan Interview Materials 1990 (Box 1)
  - Work Lists, Performances and Compositions 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  - Curriculum vitas and resumes undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous biographical information 1998-2000, undated (Box 1)
  - Performance Logistics and Specs undated (Box 1)
- Compositions and Original Scores
  The series Compositions and Original Scores documents Daugherty's activity as a composer. The series contains dozens of scores, including the original composition for the Metropolis Symphony, as well as some of Daugherty's earliest work. The series is arranged into early works and later works. The early works are arranged alphabetically by title, and the later works are organized by type of composition. Works are in composer's hand unless otherwise noted.
  - Earlier Works 1970s-1980s
    - 3 Part Invention in G Major for Solo Piano 1986 (Box 2)
    - Beams under the Action of a Moving Rhythm 1986 (Box 2)
    - Celestial Hoops, Synthesizer Soloist and Computer 1987 (Box 2)
    - Composition for Piano circa 1976 (Box 2)
    - Composition for Solo Violin 1976 (Box 2)
    - A Concert for Piano and Orchestra 1977 (Box 3)
    - A Concert for Piano and Orchestra 1977 (Box 4)
    - Crossroads for 11 Instruments 1981 (Box 5)
    - Dona Nobis Pacem 1972 (Box 1)
      Washington High School, MD's first composition
    - Ensemble Tamper for Flute, Guitar, and Cello 1981 (by Patrick Daugherty) (Box 2)
    - Eurhythmic Toccata 1983-1984 (Box 2)
    - Equipoise for Large Chamber Ensemble 1978, 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Equipoise for Large Chamber Ensemble 1978, 7 folders (Box 7)
    - A Family Gathering 1976 (Box 2)
    - Five Seasons for Orchestra 1979 (Box 8)
    - Five Seasons for Orchestra 1979 (Box 9)
    - Five Seasons for Orchestra 1979 (Box 54)
    - Flute Dance for Flute and Piano 1981 (Tanglewood) (Box 1)
    - Func-tion for Piano 1976 (Box 10)
    - Future Funk Version 1 for Percussion and Tuba and Version 2 for Trumpet and Tape 1985, 1983 (Box 10)
    - The Goodness of Unity 1979, 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Halloween for Synthesizer Quartet 1986 (Box 11)
    - Holland Music 1982-1983 (Box 1)
    - Hush for Wind Quintet 1989, 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Ivar's Two Step for Amplified Piano and Tape 1986 (Box 1)
    - Jazz Transcriptions, Early 1970s (Box 1)
    - Killer Joe, arranged for Washington High School Jazz Band 1972 (Box 1)
    - Mass 1976 (Box 11)
    - More than Three for Acoustic and Electrified Piano 1982, 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Movement for Orchestra 1974 (Box 13)
    - Music Sketches, Abandoned Holland 1982-1983 (Box 12)
    - Music Sketches, Yale undated (Box 12)
    - Musical Sketches, New York City 1978-1980, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Myth of Twilight 1977 (Box 1)
    - North Texas State University Sketches 1972-1976, 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Overture for a Necessary Event 1976 (Box 14)
    - Gil Evans Porgy and Bess Project 1980, 1 folders (Box 14)
    - Gil Evans Porgy and Bess Project 1980, 4 folders (Box 15)
    - Re: Percussion for Percussion Soloist, Synthesizers, and Keyboard Soloist 1986 (Box 16)
    - Relham for Orchestra 1972 (Box 16)
    - The Shadow is Pronounced for 8 Instruments 1978, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Short Piece for Violin and Piano 1973 (first composition) (Box 18)
    - Sketches 1972-1996 (scattered) (Box 18)
    - Sonata for Solo Piano undated (Box 19)
    - String Quintet 1976 (Box 19)
    - Strut for Piano and Computer 1979, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Trio for Flute, Violin and French Horn 1976 (Box 20)
    - Trio for Violin, Clarinet, and Piano 1974 (Box 20)
    - Walking Before Midnight 1986 (Box 20)
    - Washington High School undated (Box 1)
    - Where there is Smoke for Chamber Ensemble, Bass Baritone, and Synthesizer 1987, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Work for Big Band, Untitled circa 1982 (Box 20)
    - Yale Berio Study undated (Box 1)
    - Yale Composition Sketches undated (Box 20)
  - Later Works
    - Symphonic Band and Symphonic Winds
      - Alligator Alley for Middle-Level Band 2003 (Box 1)
      - Desi for Symphonic Winds 1991 (Box 22)
      - Lost Vegas for Symphonic Band 2011 (Box 43)
      - Niagara Falls for Symphonic Band 1997 (Box 22)
    - Percussion Ensemble
      - Lounge Lizards for 2 Pianos and 2 Percussions 1994 (Box 1)
    - Orchestra
      - Concrete Jungle-Jackie's Song for Amplified String Quartet and Orchestra 1996 (Box 22)
      - Flamingo for Orchestra 1988 (Box 44)
        (revised in 1990)
      - Ghost Ranch 2005 (Box 45)
      - Metropolis Symphony 1988-1993 (Box 22)
        - Bizarro 1993 (Box 22)
        - Krypton 1993 (Box 23)
        - Lex 1993 (Box 23)
        - MXYZPTLK 1988 (Box 24)
        - Oh Lois! 1989 (Box 24)
        - Red Cape Tango 1993 (Box 25)
        - Sketches undated (Box 25)
      - Motor City Triptych 2000 (Box 26)
      - Route 66 for Orchestra 1998 (Box 46)
      - Route 66 for Orchestra 2010-2011 (Box 54)
      - Route 66
        - Contrabass (3 versions) (Box 55)
        - Viola (5 versions) (Box 55)
        - Violin I (7 versions) (Box 55)
        - Violin II (6 versions) (Box 55)
        - Violoncello (4 versions) (Box 55)
        - Score in C 1998 (2 versions) (Box 55)
        - Score in C 1999 (Box 55)
      - Sunset Strip for Chamber Orchestra 1999 (Box 47)
      - Tell My Fortune for Orchestra 2004 (Box 26)
      - Time Machine 2003 (Box 48)
        (only percussion 1 part)
    - Concerti with Orchestra
      - Deus Ex Machina for Solo Piano and Orchestra 2007 (Box 48)
      - Fire and Blood for Violin and Orchestra 2003 (Box 27)
      - Raise the Roof for Timpani and Orchestra 2003 (Box 27)
      - Trail of Tears for Flute and Chamber Orchestra 2010 (Box 49)
    - Concerti with Symphonic Band or Symphonic Winds
      - The Gospel According to Sister Aimee 2012 (Box 50)
        (2 folders)
      - Ladder to the Moon 2006 (Box 48)
    - Brass Ensemble
      - Motown Metal for Symphonic Brass and Percussion 1994 (Box 27)
      - Timbuktuba for Euphoniums, Tubas, and Percussion 1995 (Box 27)
    - Chamber Ensemble
      - Blue like an Orange for Large Chamber Ensemble 1987 (Box 28)
      - Bounce for Two Bassoons 1988 (Box 28)
      - Crystal for Flute, Viola, and Guitar 2004 (Box 50)
        (for Red Cedar Chamber Music's Spillville Variations on a Theme byDvorák)
      - Dead Elvis for Bassoon and Small Chamber Ensemble 1993 (Box 28)
      - Firecracker for Solo Oboe and Chamber Ensemble 1988 (Box 29)
      - I Loved Lucy (Yo Amaba A Lucy) for Flute and Classical Guitar 1996 (Box 51)
      - I Loved Lucy for Flute and Guitar, undated (Box 54)
      - I Loved Lucy March 1993 (Box 54)
      - Jackie's Song for Solo Cello and Chamber Ensemble 1995 (Box 30)
      - Snap! for Large Chamber Ensemble (Box 31)
        (original parts in composer's hand and brother Pat Daugherty's hand)
      - These Boots 1998 (Box 31)
      - Viola Zombie for two violas 1991 (Box 31)
    - Chorus
      - Flying Saucer undated (Box 50)
        (for SSA Chorus)
    - Opera
      - Jackie O 1997
        - Errata and Notes 1996-1997 (Box 50)
        - Libretto 1995-1997 (Box 50)
        - Proofs and Scores 1997, 2006-2010 (Box 50)
        - Revisions -- Music and Lyrics 1996-1997, 2001, 3 folders (Box 50)
          (See additional folder in Box 51)
        - Sketches 1996-1997 (Box 51)
    - Solo Instrument
      - Monk in the Kitchen for Solo Piano 2001 (Box 52)
    - Miscellaneous
      - For String Quartet and Pre-Recorded Sound
        - Beat Boxer 1991 (Box 52)
        - Elvis Everywhere 1993 (Box 50)
        - Sing Sing: J. Edgar Hoover 1992 (Box 53)
        - Sing Sing: J. Edgar Hoover circa 2005, 2010, undated (Box 54)
        - Sing Sing: J. Edgar Hoover, Viola (2 versions) (Box 55)
        - Sing Sing: J. Edgar Hoover, Violin I (2 versions) (Box 55)
        - Sing Sing: J. Edgar Hoover, Violin II (2 versions) (Box 55)
        - Sing Sing: J. Edgar Hoover, Violoncello (2 versions) (Box 55)
      - General
        - KKK 1993 (Box 50)
          (selection from "Bang on a Can" Marathon)
      - Arrangements
        - Mendelssohn Octet -- Double Bass Arrangement 2001 (Box 52)
          (used for the Detroit Symphony Orchestra)
- Programs
  Programs contains programs from performances of Daugherty's compositions from 1973-2012.
  - 1973 (Box 32)
  - 1974 (Box 32)
  - 1975 (Box 32)
  - 1978 (Box 32)
  - 1980 (Box 32)
  - 1981 (Box 32)
  - 1984 (Box 32)
  - 1985 (Box 32)
  - 1986 (Box 32)
  - 1987 (Box 32)
  - 1988 (Box 32)
  - 1989 (Box 32)
  - 1990 (Box 32)
  - 1991 (Box 32)
  - 1992 (Box 32)
  - 1993 (Box 32)
  - 1994 (Box 32)
  - 1995 (Box 32)
  - 1996 (Box 32)
  - 1997 (Box 32)
  - 1998 (Box 32)
  - 1999 (Box 32)
  - 2000, 2 folders (Box 32)
  - 2001, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - 2002, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - 2003, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - 2004 (Box 33)
  - 2005 (Box 33)
  - 2006, 2 folders (Box 33)
  - 2007, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - 2008, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - 2009 (Box 34)
  - 2010 (Box 34)
  - 2011, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - 2012, 3 folders (Box 34)
  - 2013, 2 folders (Box 34)
- Previews
  The Previews series contains previews of performances of Daugherty's compositions.
  - 1975 (Box 34)
  - 1978 (Box 34)
  - 1979 (Box 34)
  - 1980 (Box 34)
  - 1981 (Box 34)
  - 1984 (Box 34)
  - 1985 (Box 34)
  - 1986 (Box 34)
  - 1987 (Box 34)
  - 1988 (Box 34)
  - 1989 (Box 34)
  - 1990 (Box 34)
  - 1991 (Box 34)
  - 1992 (Box 34)
  - 1993 (Box 34)
  - 1994 (Box 34)
  - 1995 (Box 34)
  - 1996 (Box 34)
  - 1997, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - 1998 (Box 35)
  - 1999 (Box 35)
  - 2000 (Box 35)
  - 2001 (Box 35)
  - 2002 (Box 35)
  - 2003 (Box 35)
  - 2004 (Box 35)
  - 2005 (Box 35)
  - 2006 (Box 35)
  - 2007 (Box 35)
  - 2008 (Box 35)
  - 2009 (Box 35)
  - 2010 (Box 35)
  - 2011 (Box 35)
- Reviews
  The Reviews series documents the critical reception of various performances of Daugherty's compositions and provides documentation of contemporary views of his creative work.
  - 1979 (Box 35)
  - 1980 (Box 35)
  - 1981 (Box 35)
  - 1982 (Box 35)
  - 1983 (Box 35)
  - 1984 (Box 35)
  - 1985 (Box 35)
  - 1986 (Box 35)
  - 1987 (Box 35)
  - 1988 (Box 35)
  - 1989 (Box 35)
  - 1990 (Box 35)
  - 1991 (Box 35)
  - 1992 (Box 35)
  - 1993 (Box 35)
  - 1994 (Box 35)
  - 1995 (Box 35)
  - 1996 (Box 35)
  - 1997, 2 folders (Box 35)
  - 1998 (Box 35)
  - 1999 (Box 35)
  - 2000 (Box 35)
  - 2001 (Box 35)
  - 2002 (Box 35)
  - 2003 (Box 35)
  - 2004 (Box 35)
  - 2005 (Box 35)
  - 2006 (Box 35)
  - 2007 (Box 35)
  - 2008 (Box 35)
  - 2009 (Box 35)
  - 2010 (Box 35)
  - 2011 (Box 35)
  - 2012 (Box 35)
- Brochures and other promotional materials
  Brochures and Other Promotional Materials document the promotion of Daugherty's work through brochures, posters, newsletters, flyers, and mailings.
  - Undated (Box 35)
  - 1987 (Box 35)
  - 1988-1989 (Box 35)
  - 1989 (Box 35)
  - 1991-1992 (Box 35)
  - 1992-1993 (Box 35)
  - 1993 (Box 35)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 35)
  - 1994-1995 (Box 35)
  - 1995 (Box 35)
  - 1995-1996 (Box 35)
  - 1996 (Box 35)
  - 1996-1997 (Box 36)
  - 1997 (Box 36)
  - 1997-1998 (Box 36)
  - 1998 (Box 36)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 36)
  - 1999 (Box 36)
  - 1999-2000 (Box 36)
  - 2000 (Box 36)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 36)
  - 2001 (Box 36)
  - 2001-2002 (Box 36)
  - 2002 (Box 36)
  - 2002-2003 (Box 36)
  - 2003 (Box 36)
  - 2003-2004 (Box 36)
  - 2004 (Box 36)
  - 2004-2005 (Box 36)
  - 2005 (Box 36)
  - 2005-2006 (Box 36)
  - 2006 (Box 36)
  - 2006-2007 (Box 36)
  - 2007 (Box 36)
  - 2007-2008 (Box 36)
  - 2008 (Box 36)
  - 2008-2009 (Box 36)
  - 2010-2011 (Box 36)
  - 2011 (Box 36)
  - 2011-2012 (Box 36)
  - 2012 (Box 36)
  - 2012-2013 (Box 36)
  - Other Promotional Materials
    - Promotional Materials undated (Box 36)
    - Boosey and Hawkes Newsletters 2005, 2011 (Box 36)
    - Faber Music Newsletter 1995-1998 (Box 36)
    - Peer Music Classical Newsletters 1994-2000 (scattered) (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous Newsletters 1999-2009 (Box 36)
    - Advertisements
      - Mailings 1987-2006 (scattered) and undated (Box 36)
      - Newspaper and Magazine Event Listings 1987-2013 (scattered) (Box 36)
      - Flyers 1986-2002 (scattered) and undated (Box 36)
      - Oversized posters of Michael Daugherty's performance (Box 31)
      - Oversized poster of Norman Phil, 2013 (Folder 1)
- Education and Awards
  The series Education and Awards includes materials related to Daugherty's undergraduate and graduate education, notes and ideas from Pierre Boulez's IRCAM, and materials from his time as a Fulbright Fellow in France. The series also documents the numerous awards and grants Daugherty has received for his work.
  - Yale University
    - Master of Musical Arts (MMA) Thesis
      - Ives, Decoration Day 1982 (Box 37)
      - Ives, Symphony # 4 1982 (Box 37)
      - Mahler-Ives Research and Notes 1982, 5 folders (Box 37)
    - Scrapbook/Albums 1982-1986, 3 folders (Box 37)
    - Binder of notes on musical compositions 1981 (Box 37)
    - Roger Reynolds Composition Class 1982 (Box 37)
    - Conducting Class with Arthur Weisburg 1981-1982 (Box 37)
    - Orchestration Class with Jacob Druckman 1982 (Box 37)
    - Shenker Class with Allen Forte 1982, 2 folders (Box 37)
    - Elliot Carter 2nd String Quartet Analysis for Theory Class with Allen Forte 1982 (Box 38)
    - "Set Theory" Class with Allen Forte 1982 (Box 38)
    - Webern Op. 21 Analysis 1982 (Box 38)
    - Oral Exam 1982 (Box 38)
    - Doctor of Musical Arts Recital Letters 1986 (Box 38)
  - Course Materials
    - North Texas State University -- Bachelor of Music 1972-1976 (Box 38)
    - Manhattan School of Music -- Master of Music 1976-1978 (Box 38)
  - Transcripts -- North Texas State University and Manhattan School of Music 1976, 1978 (Box 38)
  - Fellowships
    - Fulbright
      - France 1979, 2 folders (Box 38)
        (includes Daugherty's application)
      - IRCAM (Paris, France) and Boulez Lecture Notes and Ideas for "Pan" for computer 1979-1980 (Box 38)
    - Rotary Fellowship -- Germany 1982 (Box 38)
  - Manhattan School of Music Recommendations 1979 (Box 38)
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters Award 1991 (Box 38)
  - Michigan Arts Award 2004 (Box 38)
  - Guggenheim Award 1996 (Box 38)
  - Miscellaneous Awards 1979-2013 (scattered) (Box 38)
  - Grants 1989-1995 (scattered) (Box 38)
- Correspondence
  The eighth series, Correspondence, contains Daugherty's correspondence with other performers, symphonies, those assisting with research on his compositions, those involved with the Jackie O production, the University of Michigan and University officials, and recording companies. The series is the principal documentation of the business-side of his career.
  - From Performers, composers, and other single persons 1986-2005 (scattered), 2 folders (Box 38)
  - University Business 1986-2007 (scattered) (Box 38)
  - University-Affiliated Persons 1989-2004 (scattered) (Box 38)
  - Business Letters (Non-University) 1993-2006 (scattered) (Box 38)
  - Composition Research 1991-1999 (scattered)
    - Cadillac Ranch 1997-1999 (scattered) (Box 38)
    - Hoover 1991-1994 (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous circa 1994-1996 (Box 38)
  - Jackie O Production 1994-2005
    - Houston Grand Opera 1995-1997 (Box 38)
    - Metz Opera Theatre 2001-2002 (Box 38)
    - University of Michigan 1995-1996, 2005 (Box 38)
    - Wayne Koestenbaum 1994-1997, 2005 (Box 38)
  - Commissioning Projects 1990-2005 (scattered) (Box 39)
  - From Symphonies 1996-2004 (scattered) (Box 39)
  - Visits, Schedules, and Itineraries 1985-2006 (scattered) (Box 39)
  - Sony Classical 1994-1995 (Box 39)
  - Nonesuch Records 1996 (Box 39)
  - Naxos 2004 (Box 39)
  - Deca/Argo
    - Jackie O 1997 (Box 39)
    - Metropolis 1995-1996 (Box 39)
    - Miscellaneous 1995-1996 (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous Recording Companies 1992-2012 (scattered) (Box 39)
  - Peer Southern Music 1992-1996 (scattered) (Box 39)
  - Faber Music 1994-1998, 2 folders (Box 39)
  - Miscellaneous from Publishers 1993-1999 (Box 39)
- Contacts and Calendars
  The Contacts and Calendars series contains material related to Daugherty's professional contacts and schedule. Included are contact lists and weekly and monthly calendars.
  - Contacts 1996-2003 (scattered) (Box 39)
  - Pocket Calendars 1985-1986 (Box 39)
  - Wall Calendar 1989 (Box 31)
- Media
  The Media series contains CDs of Daugherty's work, a DVD, and photographs. Several CDs include his work in a thematic collection of pieces by various composers. The DVD is of Daugherty's Jackie O, a musical that was co-commissioned by the Houston Grand Opera and the Banff Centre. The photographs in this series are of Daugherty and the Jackie O production.
  - CDs (Box 40)
    - American Icons 1998 (Box 40)
    - American Originals 2004 (Box 40)
      (features Daugherty's Tell My Fortune)
    - Brooklyn Bridge 2005 (Box 40)
      (features Daugherty's Brooklyn Bridge)
    - Equilibrium 2003 (Box 40)
    - Fire and Blood 2009 (Box 40)
    - Letters from Lincoln 2010 (Box 40)
    - Metropolis Symphony
      - 1996 (Box 40)
      - 2009 (Box 40)
    - Philadelphia Stories / UFO 2004 (Box 40)
    - Raise the Roof 2007 (Box 40)
    - Route 66 2011 (Box 40)
    - UFO 2001 (Box 40)
  - DVDs
    - Jackie O 2009 (Box 40)
  - Photographs
    - Daugherty undated (Box 41)
    - Jackie O
      - Banff Arts Festival -- Production 1997 (Box 41)
      - Cercle Lyrique De Metz -- Rehearsals circa 2000 (Box 41)
- Published Scores
  The Published Scores series contains bound, published versions of Daugherty's scores. Included in this series are two different printings of Red Cape Tango from the Metropolis Symphony The dates of the scores reflect the first printed or copyright dates.
  - Bounce for Two Bassoons 1989 (Box 41)
  - Crystal for Flute, Alto Flute, and Piano 2006 (Box 41)
  - Dead Elvis for Small Chamber Ensemble 2000 (Box 41)
  - Fire and Blood for Violin and Orchestra 2009 (Box 41)
  - Ghost Ranch for Orchestra 2006 (Box 41)
  - The High and the Mighty for Piano and Piccolo 2000 (Box 41)
  - Metropolis Symphony
    - Krypton for Orchestra 1999 (Box 41)
    - Lex for Orchestra 2005 (Box 41)
    - Mxyzptlk for Orchestra 1997 (Box 41)
    - Oh, Lois! for Orchestra 1990 (Box 41)
    - Red Cape Tango for Orchestra 1999 (Box 41)
    - Red Cape Tango for Symphonic Band 1998 (Box 41)
      (arranged by Mark Spede)
  - Motown Metal for Brass Ensemble and Percussion 2000 (Box 41)
  - Raise the Roof for Timpani and Symphonic Band 2007 (Box 41)
  - Snap! for Large Chamber Ensemble 1998 (Box 41)
  - Tell My Fortune for Orchestra 2009 (Box 41)
  - Viola Zombie for Two Violas 1993 (Box 41)
- Teaching Materials